<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Auf das Leben!]]></title>
  <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-28T17:39:57+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Haosheng Hou]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Life Expands]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/how-life-expands.html"/>
    <updated>2017-02-02T11:49:06+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/how-life-expands</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes I wonder about how life expands beyond my expectations. It&rsquo;s already start of February in 2017. I cannot catch the pace of intensive work. But why hustle? <!--more-->Life should be flow like milk from silver spoon, not waterfall. It&rsquo;s still start of 2017. I met interesting people from different places. I went to places I&rsquo;ve never been to. I had chance that I&rsquo;ve never imagined. I also fucked up things.</p>

<p>Lack of motivation could be a huge problem at the start of 2017. It&rsquo;s gonna be a rough start. But I think I&rsquo;m confident enough to manage it.</p>

<p>Think bigger.
Be proactive.
Stay positive.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iOS Contacts Ordering Chaos]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/iOS-contacts-ordering-chaos.html"/>
    <updated>2016-05-17T16:21:51+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/iOS-contacts-ordering-chaos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a problem that confused me for quite some time. Luckily and accidentally, I found out the solution to this problem. This is really a good news for guys who have obsessive compulsive disorder.<!--more--></p>

<p>Continue reading this if you</p>

<ul>
<li>have Chinese names in your contacts</li>
<li>set your system language to English or German or whatever</li>
</ul>


<p>Requirements:</p>

<ul>
<li>Xcode from Mac</li>
<li>iCloud synchronization for contacts between iOS and Mac OS</li>
<li>Internet access</li>
</ul>


<p>Simple steps goes like this:</p>

<ol>
<li>Download ZIP from <a href="https://github.com/lexrus/PhoneticContacts">Github</a></li>
<li>Decompress the dowloaded file and double click <em>PhoneticContacts.xcodeproj</em></li>
<li>Access Xcode and run the code &ndash;> 「Build Success」</li>
<li>Wait for iCloud to synchronize.</li>
</ol>


<p>Source: <a href="http://sspai.com/23168">http://sspai.com/23168</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything Is a Pattern]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/everything-is-a-pattern.html"/>
    <updated>2016-05-13T13:18:20+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/everything-is-a-pattern</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Everything is a pattern. This sound a little bit cliche. But to be honest, cliche is the thing that always stay true. A way a person behaves can be a pattern. The way that an organization works can be a pattern. This could goes to the working efficiency area. And that&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;m going to say in this article.<!--more--></p>

<p><em>Noizio</em> is an Application that I&rsquo;m using to developing my working pattern. It has a lot of scenes of sound built in it. For example, October Rain, Coffee House, Wind Chimes and so on. You can also save your favorite composition so you can easily reuse it. For me, I usually use two patterns, daywork and nightwork. The daywork pattern is composed of Coffee House and Wind Chimes, because I really like the noise in the coffee house while working. Don&rsquo;t ask why, I&rsquo;m weird. The nightwork pattern is composed of Thundstorm and Campfire. This always reminds me of a scene in the cave, very cozy and warm, however, it rains pretty hard outside. Besides, the sound of fire always reminds me of my childhood spent in my grandma&rsquo;s house.</p>

<p>In iOS, there&rsquo;s a similar App called <em>Taomix</em>. I barely use it because I always on my Mac while I&rsquo;m working. But this App works as good as the aforementioned one, or even better. Becasue in this App you can actually define the distance of each sound source from you. I&rsquo;ve got admit that this is pretty damn cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blah Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/blah-time.html"/>
    <updated>2016-05-09T22:06:11+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/blah-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Midnight is a good time just for blah blah. One 500ml Kölsch is not enough to make me tipsy, but the weather is. Summer night is one of my favorite time to start thinking and writing stuff. This time, I&rsquo;ll quote some scripts from a movie I just saw.<!--more--></p>

<p>At the end of last year, I talked with a friend of mine about the current status I&rsquo;m in. Surprisingly I found myself to be in the way of developing a pattern of consistently getting better, no matter at relationships, or life perspectives.</p>

<blockquote><p>I&rsquo;ve been thinking that the time we have to be single, is really the time we have to get good at being alone. But, how good at being alone do we really want to be? Isn&rsquo;t there a danger that you&rsquo;ll get so good at being single, so set in your ways that you&rsquo;ll miss out the chance to be with somebody great? Some people take baby steps to settle down. Some people refuse to settle at all. Sometimes, it&rsquo;s not statistics. It&rsquo;s just chemistry. And sometimes, just because it is over, doesn&rsquo;t mean the love ends. The thing about being single is, you should cherish it. Because, in a week, or a lifetime of being alone, you may get only one moment. One moment, when you&rsquo;re not tied up in a relationship with anyone. A parent, a pet, a sibling, a friend. One moment, when you stand on your own. Really, truely single. And then, it&rsquo;s gone.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auto-sleeping in Win10]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/auto-sleeping-in-win10.html"/>
    <updated>2016-05-08T18:59:55+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/auto-sleeping-in-win10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A couple of months ago, I installed Win10 Education on my old laptop to make it a backup computer at home. But I haven&rsquo;t use it very often until today. And yet I discovered a problem that I never run into before. <!--more-->My laptop goes to sleep every 2 minutes if you don&rsquo;t operate anything. Thinking like a normal person, I certainly goes to the system setting to change the sleep option to 「Never」. Am I too naive? It turns out that I am. Changing the settings won&rsquo;t make a difference in this case.So, a little research being made and here goes the solution.</p>

<ol>
<li>Press 「WIN+r」, type in 「regedit.exe」</li>
<li><p>Locate to the following path:</p>

<pre><code> HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\Control\Power\
 PowerSettings\238C9FA8-0AAD-41ED-83F4-97BE242C8F20\
 7bc4a2f9-d8fc-4469-b07b-33eb785aaca0   
</code></pre></li>
<li><p>Change the value of 「Attributes」to 2</p></li>
<li>Press 「WIN+x」, go to 「Control Panel」->「System and Security」->「Power Options」->「Change advanced power settings」->「Sleep」->「System unattended sleep timeout」, change the time to whatever you want.</li>
</ol>


<p>Tada! Problem solved.</p>

<p>Source: <a href="https://www.zhihu.com/question/39263412/answer/87430653">https://www.zhihu.com/question/39263412/answer/87430653</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Retrospect]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/in-retrospect.html"/>
    <updated>2016-04-30T10:35:40+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/in-retrospect</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time flies. I can&rsquo;t believe that this is the first phrase that I come up with when I start to write this blog. But somehow it reflects what I feel these days. It has been one month and a half since my internship. Every week is like a flying arrow, throwing me from Monday to Friday.<!--more--></p>

<p>Almost half of 2016 has passed, I think it&rsquo;s time to do a retrospect and also some tweaking on the new year resolution that I made in January. Everything seems to be on track, except the photo shooting project. The probelem is that I don&rsquo;t have much time to contact partners to do this project, which is kind of the most important part of the theme 「parallel world」. Instead, I accidentally start a serie of photos named like 「Some XXX」, which includes the photos I&rsquo;ve taken before and some re-editing. Besides, I also had the chance to know a bunch of interesting people from Instagram. Maybe I should change the direction of the project to street photography first. Recently I&rsquo;ve been inspired by a guy named Erik Kim, who really like to share the experience during his shooting on streets. And great people skills also. I find this kind of project maybe doable, for example, 「Faces in Aachen」or something.</p>

<p>Lack of motivation is the biggest problem I&rsquo;ve been facing recently. I find it to be related to multitasking. When I assign so many tasks to myself at once, I sometimes get confused about the priorities of different tasks. This can be a source of procrastination, which means you cannot decide which ones to do first, you don&rsquo;t start at all.</p>

<p>That would be all. Set up the daily routine and get the machine running!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Markdown Is the New Sexy]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/markdown-is-the-new-sexy.html"/>
    <updated>2016-02-15T19:28:30+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/markdown-is-the-new-sexy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Markdown is a lightweight markup language developed by John Gruber(so says Wikipedia). My first contact with markdown is the time I build this personal blog website. All the blogs I&rsquo;ve written is in markdown format. This is a pretty cool and most of all distraction-free way of writing articles.<!--more--></p>

<p>But first of all, when you write something, editor is necessary. There are countless editors, well, that&rsquo;s exaggerative expression. Luckily, I only tried out three before I found my favorite one. The first one I tried is <em>Mou</em> developed by this great guy <em>Chen Luo</em>. It&rsquo;s completely free and easy to use. But the only thing that turn me down is the coloring, way too colorful for me. The second one is <em>Ulysses</em>, said to be the most powerful markdown tools on the market. Well, for me, maybe too powerful. I don&rsquo;t really need all the file directory stuff. Besides, the downside of powerful is that it&rsquo;ll definitely become slower. So comes the third one, my favorite, <em>Byword</em>. It&rsquo;s small, single-functional. Just the way I like it, full &lsquo;minimalism&rsquo; design.</p>

<p>There are already tons of tutorials on the internet about markdown grammar. However, I&rsquo;ll write another simple one and post it later, just as a reminder for me to check when I forget about something. But if this can be a little help of you guys, I&rsquo;ll be glad.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parallel World]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/parallel-world.html"/>
    <updated>2016-02-11T18:43:23+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/parallel-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the very start of 2016, I&rsquo;ve made a new year resolution list. Doing a photo-shooting project is one of them. Inspired by many photographers, I think doing a long-term project is kinda cool. Because as one German proverb goes, Anfangen ist leicht, Beharren eine Kunst, which means, starting is easy, but persistence is an art. <!--more--></p>

<p>The idea &lsquo;Parallel World&rsquo; comes from one of my favorite writers, Haruki Murakami, who wrote many of his novels in parallel. This thing about difference and coherence between different space and time really interest me. Just imagine, at 5pm, I just get out of work, cooking dinner in the kitchen while drinking some beer. In the mean time, in the parallel world, somebody is reading a bedtime book or doing other crazy things.</p>

<p>Photography is all about telling stories. By combining the photos taken in two separate while consistent world, may intriging some fantastic sparkles. That&rsquo;s the initiation.</p>

<p>However, still finding interesting people to work with, but certainly will deliver.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2016 New Year Resolution]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/2016-new-year-resolution.html"/>
    <updated>2016-01-01T22:10:13+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/2016-new-year-resolution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After getting into college, my life starts on a flying mode. This freaks me out sometimes. That’s why I tend to make plans for everything I might want to do in the next period. Although some of them did not goes out as I planned or expected, but as the saying goes, 「Never go out there without a solid plan.」<!--more--></p>

<p>2015 turned out to be not so great for me. I believe that I messed up things a little bit. With the freedom here I got in German university, I kinda loosen up a bit. And this is definitely have bad influence on me. There are some milestoney events like, breaking up with my girlfriend, passing all exams and getting a internship in the God-forsaken blackforest. For the first half in 2015, I was pretty not happy about it. My whole living routine was struggling with thesis and science projects in college, that was a huge dose of anxiety. The later half turned out a little bit better. I finally passed the toughest exams and got a internship. Big events here is moving, I think, both spatially and spiritually. I had to face the fact that I live alone in the blackforest now and it is perfect for one to do some deep thinking, to literally figure out what’s next and cut out all the unrealistic delusions. Sort of self-sustained in the later half, that’s the big accomplishments for me.</p>

<p>2016 is a big year for me. This is the year I’m really starts thinking about getting 30 would look like, which means I really should not just go with the flow and play around and stuff. This is the time that I should plan the so called “future”. What I really want to do with my life, something to be considered such as career. Besides, I believe my life-long partner is still out there waiting for me to find. So, let’s talk about resolutions.</p>

<p>In the new year, I wish I could accomplish the following things in my life.</p>

<blockquote><p>Graduate</p>

<p>Get a job</p>

<p>Learn to do handstand</p>

<p>Contact more with friends and family</p>

<p>Starting a photo-shooting project</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My 100 Thing Challenge]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/my-100-thing-challenge.html"/>
    <updated>2015-12-04T21:30:34+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/my-100-thing-challenge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>「100-Thing Challenge」 is a method to quantify your personal effort to simplify your life. This allow people to be more with less.</p>

<p>So, I decide to give it a try. I just want to see how many things I must have to keep to make my life get going. <!--more--></p>

<p>As this post originally created in 2015, I have come up with a incomplete list about my current life.</p>

<p>Wardrobe</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Outerwear</p>

<ol>
<li>Jacket black leather 1 piece</li>
<li>Jacket black bomber 1 piece</li>
<li>Coat grey Chesterfield 1 piece</li>
<li>Coat light brown short 1 piece</li>
<li>Sport blue winter 1 piece</li>
<li>Suits darkblue</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>Pants &amp; Belt</p>

<ol>
<li>Jeans dark blue 1 pair</li>
<li>Jeans light blue 1 pair</li>
<li>Khaki light brown 1 pair</li>
<li>Casual black 1 pair</li>
<li>Sport dark blue 2 pairs</li>
<li>Belt leather black 1 piece</li>
<li>Belt knit black 1 piece</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>Shoes</p>

<ol>
<li>Boots Marco Polo light brown desert 1 pair</li>
<li>Boots Timberland yellow 1 pair</li>
<li>Derby Timberland dark brown 1 pair</li>
<li>Derby black dress 1 pair</li>
<li>Loafer brown 1 pair</li>
<li>Sneaker Converse Chuck Taylor All-Stars white 1 pair</li>
<li>Running shoes New Balance M574 black outdoor 1 pair</li>
<li>Running shoes Nike red indoor 1 pair</li>
<li>Slipper 1 pair</li>
<li>Flip Flops 1 pair</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>Shirt &amp; Tie &amp; Sweater &amp; Hoodies &amp; T-Shirt</p>

<ol>
<li>Shirt light blue 1 piece</li>
<li>Shirt light green 1 piece</li>
<li>Shirt grey 1 piece</li>
<li>Shirt dark green 1 piece</li>
<li>Shirt white dress 2 piece</li>
<li>Tie skinny black 1 piece</li>
<li>Tie seven-fold blue with white dots 1 piece</li>
<li>Sweater black round neck 1 piece</li>
<li>Sweater black and white cardigan 1 piece</li>
<li>Hoodie black SuperDry Logo 1 piece</li>
<li>T-shirt pure black 2 piece</li>
<li>T-shirt pure white 3 piece</li>
<li>T-shirt black Tommy Hilfiger Logo 1 piece</li>
<li>T-shirt dark blue color front 1 piece</li>
<li>T-shirt dark blue V-neck 1 piece</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>Underwear &amp; Towel</p>

<ol>
<li>Boxer Briefs 6 pairs</li>
<li>Boxer 3 pairs</li>
<li>Socks long coloured  5 pairs</li>
<li>Socks long black 5 pairs</li>
<li>Socks no show black 5 pairs</li>
<li>Socks low cut</li>
<li>Tank Top black</li>
<li>Tank Top white</li>
<li>Lange Unterhose 3 pair</li>
<li>Sleeping pants 1 pair</li>
<li>Towel short 1 piece</li>
<li>Towel long 1 piece</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>Bags</p>

<ol>
<li>Messenger Bag brown leather &amp; knit</li>
<li>Backpack Herschel Navy</li>
<li>Backpack Kanken Fjallraven Navy</li>
<li>Briefcase Samsonite black</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Life Tool &amp; Accessories</p>

<ol>
<li>Keys</li>
<li>ID cards &amp; Bank card &amp; Wallet</li>
<li>OHROPAX Earplugs</li>
<li>Guitar</li>
<li>Toothbrush normal 1 piece</li>
<li>Toothbrush electrical 1 piece</li>
<li>Sunglass Ray-Ban Wayfarer 1 pair</li>
<li>Eyeglass Prescription Ray-Ban 1 pair</li>
<li>Dress watch DW 1 piece</li>
<li>Casual watch Casio 1 piece</li>
</ol>


<p>Electronics</p>

<ol>
<li>MacBook Pro 15’ Retina Mid 2014 + power</li>
<li>Mouse Logitech bluetooth M557</li>
<li>Kindle PaperWhite + power</li>
<li>iPhone 7 128G + power</li>
<li>iPad 4 32G + power</li>
<li>iPod Shuffle 8G + power</li>
<li>Jabra Revo Wireless Headphone + power</li>
<li>JBL Bluetooth Speaker + power</li>
<li>Canon 70d + multiple lens and accessories</li>
<li>WD MyPassport portable drive 500G</li>
</ol>


<p>(To be completed&hellip;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setup Workflow on Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/setup-workflow-on-mac.html"/>
    <updated>2015-11-14T20:02:05+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/setup-workflow-on-mac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As this may sounds familier to all of you: before I start doing my work, I just use 5 minutes to check out the new post on Facebook or Twitter. And a hour has passed, you are kind of &ldquo;stuck to&rdquo; the virtual circle of intersting things. This happens to me all the time. Works are always be postponed, things remain undone, life sucks.<!--more--></p>

<p>I think the most exciting and frustrating thing about Mac is that, you don&rsquo;t need to shut down. If you were social-networking, the next time you open up you Mac, you will directly be in the same status. However, if you think on the opposite way, you will discover that the work you left there yesterday are still there. Instead of seeing social network page on the first sight, you will continue to do your work instantly.</p>

<p>Workflow maybe the best thing I could think of to avoid distraction. With one click or type in the terminal some command, you will quickly pick up the work you left and get in the mood of working.Here goes how:</p>

<p>The workflow to quit all Applications:</p>

<blockquote><ol>
<li><p>Open Automator and choose workflow</p></li>
<li><p>In the Library, choose Utilities, then drag 「Quit all Applications」to the right</p></li>
<li><p>If you wanna keep some App open, just hit 「Add current Applications」</p></li>
</ol>
</blockquote>

<p>The workflow to open certain bundle of Applications is basically the same procedure, one can explore a little bit.</p>

<p>cmd+s to save the work flow and just pin it somewhere handy, dock seems to be a excellent choice.  Or if you prefer the using of Terminal, you can type in the following command:</p>

<pre><code>automator yourworkflow.workflow
</code></pre>

<p>in the path where you saved your workflow.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s also a tip for setting workflow. You have to know exactly what you gonna do with your Mac, probably write all the Application you need and the sequence maybe on Notes, and then set up the workflow. As always, with explicit target, you can avoid wasting time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Tips for Excel VBA]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/useful-tips-for-excel-vba.html"/>
    <updated>2015-11-13T22:52:37+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/useful-tips-for-excel-vba</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I&rsquo;ve been working intensively with Excel VBA to achieve some automation of data processing and analysing. During my first approches to use VBA, I found some really useful tips for newbies in this area.<!--more--></p>

<h2>1.Think Before Coding.</h2>

<p>This is definitely the iron-rule of coding, regardless of the programming language. You have to fully understand what problem are you solving, which function or method do you need exactly for this problem. I will introduce some useful steps for clearing the problem and also get to know what you are really facing in the following text.</p>

<h2>2.Use Immediate Window</h2>

<p>This is a useful function that embedded in Excel. You can get instant result of your command in this window, therefore, it is a really good friend while you are debugging.</p>

<h2>3.Use Debug.Print</h2>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t know what results your stated formula in VBA will get, this is the one command you should turn to for some help. Just simply type in the command and add the variable you want to know after the command.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Useful Debug</span></figcaption>
<div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='VB.net'><span class='line'><span class="n">Debug</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Print</span> <span class="n">Variable</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h2>4.Always Break Your Work Into Smaller Pieces</h2>

<p>I will show you how this works through a really simple example. My task would be add a button into the worksheet, it can achieve the function of copying certain range of values and paste it somewhere. I will first disassemble this task into 3 steps.</p>

<blockquote><p>1.Write code about the function of copy and paste</p>

<p>2.Add a button to the worksheet</p>

<p>3.Assign the function to the button</p></blockquote>

<p>Of course, you can further disassemble step one, maybe first learn about the knowledge of &ldquo;Range&rdquo; object. It depends on your level.</p>

<h2>5.Build Iteratively To Fully Understand The Task</h2>

<p>Maybe for people not familier with programming, this is a good approach. For iterative problems, we have to consider all the conditions and loops. With listing some of them without loop, you can get a better and straightforward view of your task. This can save a lot of work if you write your loops wrong and debugging afterwards.</p>

<h2>6.Refer Not Only to Internet, But Also Refer To A Good Book</h2>

<p>Internet is a useful tool for some instant problems. But if you want to use VBA for a long term, you may better invest more time on learning it through a book. To be honest, I don&rsquo;t really have that much time to read the book, but I&rsquo;ve found some really useful conceptural knowledge in the following book.</p>

<blockquote><p>Excel Power Programming with VBA by John Walkenbach</p></blockquote>

<h2>7.Always Optimize Your Code and Speedup</h2>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Optimization</span></figcaption>
<div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='VB.net'><span class='line'><span class="err">‘</span><span class="n">turn</span> <span class="n">off</span> <span class="n">some</span> <span class="n">Excel</span> <span class="n">functionality</span> <span class="n">so</span> <span class="n">your</span> <span class="n">code</span> <span class="n">runs</span> <span class="n">faster</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">Application</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">ScreenUpdating</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">False</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">Application</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">DisplayStatusBar</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">False</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">Application</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Calculation</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">xlCalculationManual</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">Application</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">EnableEvents</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">False</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">ActiveSheet</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">DisplayPageBreaks</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">False</span>      <span class="err">‘</span><span class="n">note</span> <span class="n">this</span> <span class="ow">is</span> <span class="n">a</span> <span class="n">sheet</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">level</span> <span class="n">setting</span>
</span><span class='line'>  
</span><span class='line'><span class="err">‘</span><span class="n">Your</span> <span class="n">code</span> <span class="n">here</span>
</span><span class='line'>  
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">Application</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">ScreenUpdating</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">screenUpdateState</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">Application</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">DisplayStatusBar</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">statusBarState</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">Application</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Calculation</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">calcState</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">Application</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">EnableEvents</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">eventsState</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">ActiveSheet</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">DisplayPageBreaks</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">displayPageBreaksState</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vim Learning Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/vim-notes.html"/>
    <updated>2015-10-04T19:58:12+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/vim-notes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>1.Command in Vim non-editing environment</h2>

<h3>1.1 Lowercase/Uppercase</h3>

<p>In order to change the case of the whole document in vi, the following commands can do that trick easily.<!--more-->
in lowercase:
    %s/.<em>/\L&amp;/<br/>
in uppercase:
    %s/.</em>/\U&amp;/</p>

<h3>1.2 Show line numbers</h3>

<p>If you wanna show the line numbers in vi environment, just type in the following command.
    set nu</p>

<h2>2.Moving curser</h2>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th> Key           </th>
<th> Motion        </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td> h             </td>
<td> Move left     </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> j             </td>
<td> Move down     </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> k             </td>
<td> Move up       </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> l             </td>
<td> Move right    </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
