<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Categorieseditor | Auf das Leben!]]></title>
  <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/categories/editor/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-18T13:49:13+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Haosheng Hou]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Markdown Is the New Sexy]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/markdown-is-the-new-sexy.html"/>
    <updated>2016-02-15T19:28:30+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/markdown-is-the-new-sexy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Markdown is a lightweight markup language developed by John Gruber(so says Wikipedia). My first contact with markdown is the time I build this personal blog website. All the blogs I&rsquo;ve written is in markdown format. This is a pretty cool and most of all distraction-free way of writing articles.<!--more--></p>

<p>But first of all, when you write something, editor is necessary. There are countless editors, well, that&rsquo;s exaggerative expression. Luckily, I only tried out three before I found my favorite one. The first one I tried is <em>Mou</em> developed by this great guy <em>Chen Luo</em>. It&rsquo;s completely free and easy to use. But the only thing that turn me down is the coloring, way too colorful for me. The second one is <em>Ulysses</em>, said to be the most powerful markdown tools on the market. Well, for me, maybe too powerful. I don&rsquo;t really need all the file directory stuff. Besides, the downside of powerful is that it&rsquo;ll definitely become slower. So comes the third one, my favorite, <em>Byword</em>. It&rsquo;s small, single-functional. Just the way I like it, full &lsquo;minimalism&rsquo; design.</p>

<p>There are already tons of tutorials on the internet about markdown grammar. However, I&rsquo;ll write another simple one and post it later, just as a reminder for me to check when I forget about something. But if this can be a little help of you guys, I&rsquo;ll be glad.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vim Learning Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/vim-notes.html"/>
    <updated>2015-10-04T19:58:12+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/vim-notes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>1.Command in Vim non-editing environment</h2>

<h3>1.1 Lowercase/Uppercase</h3>

<p>In order to change the case of the whole document in vi, the following commands can do that trick easily.<!--more-->
in lowercase:
    %s/.<em>/\L&amp;/<br/>
in uppercase:
    %s/.</em>/\U&amp;/</p>

<h3>1.2 Show line numbers</h3>

<p>If you wanna show the line numbers in vi environment, just type in the following command.
    set nu</p>

<h2>2.Moving curser</h2>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th> Key           </th>
<th> Motion        </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td> h             </td>
<td> Move left     </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> j             </td>
<td> Move down     </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> k             </td>
<td> Move up       </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> l             </td>
<td> Move right    </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
