<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Categorieslife | Auf das Leben!]]></title>
  <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-10-03T20:51:30+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Haosheng Hou]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Always Doing Better]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/always-doing-better.html"/>
    <updated>2018-10-03T20:03:08+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/always-doing-better</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a really long time since I ever update my blog. Things has been crazy this year. I took a quick look on the last blog I wrote at the end of 2017. I started to realize that how much I&rsquo;ve changed in 2018. <!--more--></p>

<p>First of all, I&rsquo;m getting used to the fact that I&rsquo;m not a student any more. As a fully responsible human being, I have to bear with every consequences my decisions lead to. And most importantly, I must think for my self, career-wise and life-wise. Which city? Which kind of job? Which life style? It&rsquo;t not that I haven&rsquo;t think about them before. It&rsquo;s just I need some fine tunings to my original plan. Because I have to admit, that reality have some limitations compare to my idealistic planning. I think what should remain unchanged is that I haven&rsquo;t think about fixing myself to a certain kind of life or job. I still want to have the flexibility of trying different things, which I believe is the sign of young.</p>

<p>Second, I thought another half-year in Germany would be boring AF. I was wrong. It turned out that with the new people I&rsquo;ve known, I started to re-discover the fun in life. This makes me thinking that maybe I was losing my fun by hanging out the the wrong gang the whole time. I&rsquo;m not a guy that could stick with the same 9-to-5 work schedule day by day. I need excitement in life to fulfil my hobbies. I need to meet people which can bring me different perspectives in life. I need to reflect myself on a regular basis to become better. This is the reason that I hate being buried in repetitive work or paper work on a daily basis.</p>

<p>Right now, it is another critical time for decisions. No matter what the outcome is, the purpose is unanimous:</p>

<p>Always. Doing. Better.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughts on Sabbatical Year]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/some-thoughts-on-sabbatical-year.html"/>
    <updated>2017-12-05T13:11:06+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/some-thoughts-on-sabbatical-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I&rsquo;ve been reading a book called <em>Der Weg zur finanziellen Freiheit Ihre erste Million in 7 Jahren</em> by Bodo Schäfer. In this book, he explained a concept <em>Sabbatical Year</em> which is quite interesting.<!--more--></p>

<blockquote><p>Sabbatical is a rest from work, or a break, often lasting from two months to a year.</p></blockquote>

<p>Bodo made a assumption which got me thinking: What would you do if you have the whole year off and enough money to pay for all your bills in the next five years? He described his situation in the book. He did not do much in the first few weeks. Afterwards he went on travel and attending seminars. He learned to meditate, had time to read books irrelevant to his career path. Finally, he got to listen to his heart. He wanted to make plans for the future, but yet he couldn&rsquo;t find the answer.</p>

<p>Questions started to come along with this new thought. All in all, it seems that all the questions became two obvious ones:</p>

<ul>
<li>Who am I?</li>
<li>Why am I here?</li>
</ul>


<p>Sounds like the ultimate questions for human kind, right? The interesting part is when he started writing. After 11 days of intensive writing, he saw the answers vividly to these two questions. I think this means he found the ultimate goal for his life. Although I am really interested in knowing what it is.</p>

<p>The point he&rsquo;s trying to make is to address the significance of financial freedom to finding ultimate meaning for life. The prerequisite for this is you have the knowhow and the eagerness to improve, otherwise you may become the void.</p>

<p>Two perspectives from my side after getting to know his stoty:</p>

<ol>
<li>Financial freedom is crucial to finding ultimate meaning for life</li>
<li>Writing is a good way to know yourself, so do not give up on it</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life in Beijing]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/life-in-beijing.html"/>
    <updated>2017-12-03T16:04:10+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/life-in-beijing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been two months. To be honest, life in Beijing is not as smooth as one may imagine. Perhaps this is the case for every huge transition in life, especially from a small city in Europe to a huge international capital city in China. <!--more--></p>

<p>On the positive side, I had the chance to embrace all the convenience new technology offers. For example, instead of carrying chunky wallet with all the coins, I basically only need a few cards and a iPhone. With all the new things happens around and the high pace of life，I feel like I&rsquo;m a freshman at college, excited and thrilled.</p>

<p>On the not so positive side, I&rsquo;m still not getting over with mega-city-syndrome, which is a syndrome I just made up. It means that my life radius is so much expanded to every possible corner in Beijing with all the transportation methods. However, time is correspondingly wasted on the road, which causes anxiety and tiredness sometimes. I think this is the part that I need to come up plans when I really need to go somewhere, not just go with the flow.</p>

<p>The best is yet to come.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blah Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/blah-time.html"/>
    <updated>2016-05-09T22:06:11+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/blah-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Midnight is a good time just for blah blah. One 500ml Kölsch is not enough to make me tipsy, but the weather is. Summer night is one of my favorite time to start thinking and writing stuff. This time, I&rsquo;ll quote some scripts from a movie I just saw.<!--more--></p>

<p>At the end of last year, I talked with a friend of mine about the current status I&rsquo;m in. Surprisingly I found myself to be in the way of developing a pattern of consistently getting better, no matter at relationships, or life perspectives.</p>

<blockquote><p>I&rsquo;ve been thinking that the time we have to be single, is really the time we have to get good at being alone. But, how good at being alone do we really want to be? Isn&rsquo;t there a danger that you&rsquo;ll get so good at being single, so set in your ways that you&rsquo;ll miss out the chance to be with somebody great? Some people take baby steps to settle down. Some people refuse to settle at all. Sometimes, it&rsquo;s not statistics. It&rsquo;s just chemistry. And sometimes, just because it is over, doesn&rsquo;t mean the love ends. The thing about being single is, you should cherish it. Because, in a week, or a lifetime of being alone, you may get only one moment. One moment, when you&rsquo;re not tied up in a relationship with anyone. A parent, a pet, a sibling, a friend. One moment, when you stand on your own. Really, truely single. And then, it&rsquo;s gone.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Retrospect]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/in-retrospect.html"/>
    <updated>2016-04-30T10:35:40+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/in-retrospect</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time flies. I can&rsquo;t believe that this is the first phrase that I come up with when I start to write this blog. But somehow it reflects what I feel these days. It has been one month and a half since my internship. Every week is like a flying arrow, throwing me from Monday to Friday.<!--more--></p>

<p>Almost half of 2016 has passed, I think it&rsquo;s time to do a retrospect and also some tweaking on the new year resolution that I made in January. Everything seems to be on track, except the photo shooting project. The probelem is that I don&rsquo;t have much time to contact partners to do this project, which is kind of the most important part of the theme 「parallel world」. Instead, I accidentally start a serie of photos named like 「Some XXX」, which includes the photos I&rsquo;ve taken before and some re-editing. Besides, I also had the chance to know a bunch of interesting people from Instagram. Maybe I should change the direction of the project to street photography first. Recently I&rsquo;ve been inspired by a guy named Erik Kim, who really like to share the experience during his shooting on streets. And great people skills also. I find this kind of project maybe doable, for example, 「Faces in Aachen」or something.</p>

<p>Lack of motivation is the biggest problem I&rsquo;ve been facing recently. I find it to be related to multitasking. When I assign so many tasks to myself at once, I sometimes get confused about the priorities of different tasks. This can be a source of procrastination, which means you cannot decide which ones to do first, you don&rsquo;t start at all.</p>

<p>That would be all. Set up the daily routine and get the machine running!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
