<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Categorieslife | Auf das Leben!]]></title>
  <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-11T20:31:16+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Haosheng Hou]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parallel World]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/parallel-world.html"/>
    <updated>2016-02-11T18:43:23+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/parallel-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the very start of 2016, I&rsquo;ve made a new year resolution list. Doing a photo-shooting project is one of them. Inspired by many photographers, I think doing a long-term project is kinda cool. Because as one German proverb goes, Anfangen ist leicht, Beharren eine Kunst, which means, starting is easy, but persistence is an art. <!--more--></p>

<p>The idea &lsquo;Parallel World&rsquo; comes from one of my favorite writers, Haruki Murakami, who wrote many of his novels in parallel. This thing about difference and coherence between different space and time really interest me. Just imagine, at 5pm, I just get out of work, cooking dinner in the kitchen while drinking some beer. In the mean time, in the parallel world, somebody is reading a bedtime book or doing other crazy things.</p>

<p>Photography is all about telling stories. By combining the photos taken in two separate while consistent world, may intriging some fantastic sparkles. That&rsquo;s the initiation.</p>

<p>However, still finding interesting people to work with, but certainly will deliver.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2016 New Year Resolution]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/2016-new-year-resolution.html"/>
    <updated>2016-01-01T22:10:13+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/2016-new-year-resolution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After getting into college, my life starts on a flying mode. This freaks me out sometimes. That’s why I tend to make plans for everything I might want to do in the next period. Although some of them did not goes out as I planned or expected, but as the saying goes, 「Never go out there with a solid plan.」<!--more--></p>

<p>2015 turned out to be not so great for me. I believe that I messed up things a little bit. With the freedom here I got in German university, I kinda loosen up a bit. And this is definitely have bad influence on me. There are some milestoney events like, breaking up with my girlfriend, passing all exams and getting a internship in the God-forsaken blackforest. For the first half in 2015, I was pretty not happy about it. My whole living routine was struggling with thesis and science projects in college, that was a huge dose of anxiety. The later half turned out a little bit better. I finally passed the toughest exams and got a internship. Big events here is moving, I think, both spatially and spiritually. I had to face the fact that I live alone in the blackforest now and it is perfect for one to do some deep thinking, to literally figure out what’s next and cut out all the unrealistic delusions. Sort of self-sustained in the later half, that’s the big accomplishments for me.</p>

<p>2016 is a big year for me. This is the year I’m really starts thinking about getting 30 would look like, which means I really should not just go with the flow and play around and stuff. This is the time that I should plan the so called “future”. What I really want to do with my life, something to be considered such as career. Besides, I believe my life-long partner is still out there waiting for me to find. So, let’s talk about resolutions.</p>

<p>In the new year, I wish I could accomplish the following things in my life.</p>

<blockquote><p>Graduate</p>

<p>Get a job</p>

<p>Learn to do handstand</p>

<p>Contact more with friends and family</p>

<p>Starting a photo-shooting project</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
