<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Categorieslife | Auf das Leben!]]></title>
  <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-04-25T15:13:33+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Haosheng Hou]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blah Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/blah-time.html"/>
    <updated>2016-05-09T22:06:11+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/blah-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Midnight is a good time just for blah blah. One 500ml Kölsch is not enough to make me tipsy, but the weather is. Summer night is one of my favorite time to start thinking and writing stuff. This time, I&rsquo;ll quote some scripts from a movie I just saw.<!--more--></p>

<p>At the end of last year, I talked with a friend of mine about the current status I&rsquo;m in. Surprisingly I found myself to be in the way of developing a pattern of consistently getting better, no matter at relationships, or life perspectives.</p>

<blockquote><p>I&rsquo;ve been thinking that the time we have to be single, is really the time we have to get good at being alone. But, how good at being alone do we really want to be? Isn&rsquo;t there a danger that you&rsquo;ll get so good at being single, so set in your ways that you&rsquo;ll miss out the chance to be with somebody great? Some people take baby steps to settle down. Some people refuse to settle at all. Sometimes, it&rsquo;s not statistics. It&rsquo;s just chemistry. And sometimes, just because it is over, doesn&rsquo;t mean the love ends. The thing about being single is, you should cherish it. Because, in a week, or a lifetime of being alone, you may get only one moment. One moment, when you&rsquo;re not tied up in a relationship with anyone. A parent, a pet, a sibling, a friend. One moment, when you stand on your own. Really, truely single. And then, it&rsquo;s gone.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Retrospect]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/in-retrospect.html"/>
    <updated>2016-04-30T10:35:40+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/in-retrospect</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time flies. I can&rsquo;t believe that this is the first phrase that I come up with when I start to write this blog. But somehow it reflects what I feel these days. It has been one month and a half since my internship. Every week is like a flying arrow, throwing me from Monday to Friday.<!--more--></p>

<p>Almost half of 2016 has passed, I think it&rsquo;s time to do a retrospect and also some tweaking on the new year resolution that I made in January. Everything seems to be on track, except the photo shooting project. The probelem is that I don&rsquo;t have much time to contact partners to do this project, which is kind of the most important part of the theme 「parallel world」. Instead, I accidentally start a serie of photos named like 「Some XXX」, which includes the photos I&rsquo;ve taken before and some re-editing. Besides, I also had the chance to know a bunch of interesting people from Instagram. Maybe I should change the direction of the project to street photography first. Recently I&rsquo;ve been inspired by a guy named Erik Kim, who really like to share the experience during his shooting on streets. And great people skills also. I find this kind of project maybe doable, for example, 「Faces in Aachen」or something.</p>

<p>Lack of motivation is the biggest problem I&rsquo;ve been facing recently. I find it to be related to multitasking. When I assign so many tasks to myself at once, I sometimes get confused about the priorities of different tasks. This can be a source of procrastination, which means you cannot decide which ones to do first, you don&rsquo;t start at all.</p>

<p>That would be all. Set up the daily routine and get the machine running!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parallel World]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/parallel-world.html"/>
    <updated>2016-02-11T18:43:23+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/parallel-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the very start of 2016, I&rsquo;ve made a new year resolution list. Doing a photo-shooting project is one of them. Inspired by many photographers, I think doing a long-term project is kinda cool. Because as one German proverb goes, Anfangen ist leicht, Beharren eine Kunst, which means, starting is easy, but persistence is an art. <!--more--></p>

<p>The idea &lsquo;Parallel World&rsquo; comes from one of my favorite writers, Haruki Murakami, who wrote many of his novels in parallel. This thing about difference and coherence between different space and time really interest me. Just imagine, at 5pm, I just get out of work, cooking dinner in the kitchen while drinking some beer. In the mean time, in the parallel world, somebody is reading a bedtime book or doing other crazy things.</p>

<p>Photography is all about telling stories. By combining the photos taken in two separate while consistent world, may intriging some fantastic sparkles. That&rsquo;s the initiation.</p>

<p>However, still finding interesting people to work with, but certainly will deliver.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2016 New Year Resolution]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/2016-new-year-resolution.html"/>
    <updated>2016-01-01T22:10:13+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/2016-new-year-resolution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After getting into college, my life starts on a flying mode. This freaks me out sometimes. That’s why I tend to make plans for everything I might want to do in the next period. Although some of them did not goes out as I planned or expected, but as the saying goes, 「Never go out there without a solid plan.」<!--more--></p>

<p>2015 turned out to be not so great for me. I believe that I messed up things a little bit. With the freedom here I got in German university, I kinda loosen up a bit. And this is definitely have bad influence on me. There are some milestoney events like, breaking up with my girlfriend, passing all exams and getting a internship in the God-forsaken blackforest. For the first half in 2015, I was pretty not happy about it. My whole living routine was struggling with thesis and science projects in college, that was a huge dose of anxiety. The later half turned out a little bit better. I finally passed the toughest exams and got a internship. Big events here is moving, I think, both spatially and spiritually. I had to face the fact that I live alone in the blackforest now and it is perfect for one to do some deep thinking, to literally figure out what’s next and cut out all the unrealistic delusions. Sort of self-sustained in the later half, that’s the big accomplishments for me.</p>

<p>2016 is a big year for me. This is the year I’m really starts thinking about getting 30 would look like, which means I really should not just go with the flow and play around and stuff. This is the time that I should plan the so called “future”. What I really want to do with my life, something to be considered such as career. Besides, I believe my life-long partner is still out there waiting for me to find. So, let’s talk about resolutions.</p>

<p>In the new year, I wish I could accomplish the following things in my life.</p>

<blockquote><p>Graduate</p>

<p>Get a job</p>

<p>Learn to do handstand</p>

<p>Contact more with friends and family</p>

<p>Starting a photo-shooting project</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My 100 Thing Challenge]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/my-100-thing-challenge.html"/>
    <updated>2015-12-04T21:30:34+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/my-100-thing-challenge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>「100-Thing Challenge」 is a method to quantify your personal effort to simplify your life. This allow people to be more with less.</p>

<p>So, I decide to give it a try. I just want to see how many things I must have to keep to make my life get going. <!--more--></p>

<p>As this post originally created in 2015, I have come up with a incomplete list about my current life.</p>

<h2>Wardrobe</h2>

<h3>Outerwear</h3>

<pre><code>1. Jacket black leather 1 piece
2. Jacket black bomber 1 piece
3. Coat grey Chesterfield 1 piece
4. Coat light brown short 1 piece
5. Sport blue winter 1 piece
6. Suits darkblue 
</code></pre>

<h3>Pants &amp; Belt</h3>

<pre><code>1. Jeans dark blue 1 pair
2. Jeans light blue 1 pair
3. Khaki light brown 1 pair
4. Casual black 1 pair
5. Sport dark blue 2 pairs
6. Belt leather black 1 piece
7. Belt knit black 1 piece
</code></pre>

<h3>Shoes</h3>

<pre><code>1. Boots Marco Polo light brown desert 1 pair
2. Boots Timberland yellow 1 pair
3. Derby Timberland dark brown 1 pair
4. Derby black dress 1 pair
5. Loafer brown 1 pair
6. Sneaker Converse Chuck Taylor All-Stars white 1 pair
7. Running shoes New Balance M574 black outdoor 1 pair
8. Running shoes Nike red indoor 1 pair
9. Slipper 1 pair
10. Flip Flops 1 pair
</code></pre>

<h3>Shirt &amp; Tie &amp; Sweater &amp; Hoodies &amp; T-Shirt</h3>

<pre><code>1. Shirt light blue 1 piece
2. Shirt light green 1 piece
3. Shirt grey 1 piece
4. Shirt dark green 1 piece
5. Shirt white dress 2 piece
6. Tie skinny black 1 piece
7. Tie seven-fold blue with white dots 1 piece
8. Sweater black round neck 1 piece
9. Sweater black and white cardigan 1 piece
10. Hoodie black SuperDry Logo 1 piece
11. T-shirt pure black 2 piece
12. T-shirt pure white 3 piece
13. T-shirt black Tommy Hilfiger Logo 1 piece
14. T-shirt dark blue color front 1 piece
15. T-shirt dark blue V-neck 1 piece
</code></pre>

<h3>Underwear &amp; Towel</h3>

<pre><code>1. Boxer Briefs 6 pairs
2. Boxer 3 pairs
3. Socks long coloured  5 pairs
4. Socks long black 5 pairs
5. Socks no show black 5 pairs
6. Socks low cut
7. Tank Top black
8. Tank Top white 
9. Lange Unterhose 3 pair
10. Sleeping pants 1 pair
11. Towel short 1 piece
12. Towel long 1 piece
</code></pre>

<h3>Bags</h3>

<pre><code>1. Messenger Bag brown leather &amp; knit 
2. Backpack Herschel Navy 
3. Backpack Kanken Fjallraven Navy
4. Briefcase Samsonite black
</code></pre>

<h2>Life Tool &amp; Accessories</h2>

<pre><code>1. Keys
2. ID cards &amp; Bank card &amp; Wallet
3. OHROPAX Earplugs
4. Guitar
5. Toothbrush normal 1 piece
6. Toothbrush electrical 1 piece
7. Sunglass Ray-Ban Wayfarer 1 pair
8. Eyeglass Prescription Ray-Ban 1 pair
9. Dress watch DW 1 piece
10. Casual watch Casio 1 piece
</code></pre>

<h2>Electronics</h2>

<pre><code>1. MacBook Pro 15’ Retina Mid 2014 + power
2. Mouse Logitech bluetooth M557
3. Kindle PaperWhite + power
4. iPhone 7 128G + power
5. iPad 4 32G + power
6. iPod Shuffle 8G + power
7. Jabra Revo Wireless Headphone + power
8. JBL Bluetooth Speaker + power
9. Canon 70d + multiple lens and accessories
10. WD MyPassport portable drive 500G
</code></pre>

<p>(To be completed&hellip;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
