<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Categoriestech | Auf das Leben!]]></title>
  <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/categories/tech/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-03-31T14:22:18+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Haosheng Hou]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iOS Contacts Ordering Chaos]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/iOS-contacts-ordering-chaos.html"/>
    <updated>2016-05-17T16:21:51+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/iOS-contacts-ordering-chaos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a problem that confused me for quite some time. Luckily and accidentally, I found out the solution to this problem. This is really a good news for guys who have obsessive compulsive disorder.<!--more--></p>

<p>Continue reading this if you</p>

<ul>
<li>have Chinese names in your contacts</li>
<li>set your system language to English or German or whatever</li>
</ul>


<p>Requirements:</p>

<ul>
<li>Xcode from Mac</li>
<li>iCloud synchronization for contacts between iOS and Mac OS</li>
<li>Internet access</li>
</ul>


<p>Simple steps goes like this:</p>

<ol>
<li>Download ZIP from <a href="https://github.com/lexrus/PhoneticContacts">Github</a></li>
<li>Decompress the dowloaded file and double click <em>PhoneticContacts.xcodeproj</em></li>
<li>Access Xcode and run the code &ndash;> 「Build Success」</li>
<li>Wait for iCloud to synchronize.</li>
</ol>


<p>Source: <a href="http://sspai.com/23168">http://sspai.com/23168</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything Is a Pattern]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/everything-is-a-pattern.html"/>
    <updated>2016-05-13T13:18:20+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/everything-is-a-pattern</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Everything is a pattern. This sound a little bit cliche. But to be honest, cliche is the thing that always stay true. A way a person behaves can be a pattern. The way that an organization works can be a pattern. This could goes to the working efficiency area. And that&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;m going to say in this article.<!--more--></p>

<p><em>Noizio</em> is an Application that I&rsquo;m using to developing my working pattern. It has a lot of scenes of sound built in it. For example, October Rain, Coffee House, Wind Chimes and so on. You can also save your favorite composition so you can easily reuse it. For me, I usually use two patterns, daywork and nightwork. The daywork pattern is composed of Coffee House and Wind Chimes, because I really like the noise in the coffee house while working. Don&rsquo;t ask why, I&rsquo;m weird. The nightwork pattern is composed of Thundstorm and Campfire. This always reminds me of a scene in the cave, very cozy and warm, however, it rains pretty hard outside. Besides, the sound of fire always reminds me of my childhood spent in my grandma&rsquo;s house.</p>

<p>In iOS, there&rsquo;s a similar App called <em>Taomix</em>. I barely use it because I always on my Mac while I&rsquo;m working. But this App works as good as the aforementioned one, or even better. Becasue in this App you can actually define the distance of each sound source from you. I&rsquo;ve got admit that this is pretty damn cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auto-sleeping in Win10]]></title>
    <link href="http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/auto-sleeping-in-win10.html"/>
    <updated>2016-05-08T18:59:55+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://houhaosheng.github.io/blog/auto-sleeping-in-win10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://omuoa05ah.bkt.clouddn.com/win10.png" alt="Windows10" /></p>

<p>A couple of months ago, I installed Win10 Education on my old laptop to make it a backup computer at home. But I haven&rsquo;t use it very often until today. And yet I discovered a problem that I never run into before. <!--more-->My laptop goes to sleep every 2 minutes if you don&rsquo;t operate anything. Thinking like a normal person, I certainly goes to the system setting to change the sleep option to 「Never」. Am I too naive? It turns out that I am. Changing the settings won&rsquo;t make a difference in this case.So, a little research being made and here goes the solution.</p>

<ol>
<li>Press 「WIN+r」, type in 「regedit.exe」</li>
<li><p>Locate to the following path:</p>

<pre><code> HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\Control\Power\
 PowerSettings\238C9FA8-0AAD-41ED-83F4-97BE242C8F20\
 7bc4a2f9-d8fc-4469-b07b-33eb785aaca0   
</code></pre></li>
<li><p>Change the value of 「Attributes」to 2</p></li>
<li>Press 「WIN+x」, go to 「Control Panel」->「System and Security」->「Power Options」->「Change advanced power settings」->「Sleep」->「System unattended sleep timeout」, change the time to whatever you want.</li>
</ol>


<p>Tada! Problem solved.</p>

<p>Source: <a href="https://www.zhihu.com/question/39263412/answer/87430653">https://www.zhihu.com/question/39263412/answer/87430653</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
